第一部分，我们将创建一个定制的盖茨比主题。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Part 1, we're
going to create a custom Gatsby theme.
这将是一个文档主题，并将使用 MDX。
It's gonna be a documentation theme,
and that's going to use MDX.
如果你看过我为《了不起的盖茨比》做的另一个工作坊
If you've watched the the other
workshop that I did on Gatsby it for
前端主机我们使用 MDX。
front end masters we use MDX.
但是如果你以前没有用过 MDX，别担心，我们会在这里全部介绍。
But if you haven't used MDX before, don't
worry, we're gonna cover all of it here.
我们将定义一些自定义数据类型。
We're gonna define some custom data type.
所以我们要定义一个实际的文档页面，使用 MDX 的通用类型。
So we're gonna define an actual docs page,
generic type that uses MDX.
我们将使用的主题用户界面，这是一个美妙的图书馆从杰克逊布莱克
We'll use Theme UI which is a wonderful
library from Jackson Black that
允许我们设置颜色和字体大小
allows us to kind of set up colors and
font sizes and
以一种易于组合和分享的方式。
things in a way that's composable and
easy to share.
我们还将添加对实时编辑示例代码的支持。
We will also add support for
live edited example code.
我们将使用来自强大实验室的实时反应。
We're gonna be using react
live from Formidable Labs.
展示代码示例和代码示例的结果是一种非常酷的方式
It's a really cool way to show a code
sample and the result of that code sample
以便有人可以编辑并立即看到结果。
in a way that somebody can edit and
see the results immediately.
然后，一旦我们完成了这一步，我们将安装自定义主题
Then, once we're done with that, we're
going to install that custom theme on
我建立了一个假的 JavaScript 库，然后我决定我不能这么做
an existing site I built a fake JavaScript
library and then I decided I couldn't
有一个假的 JavaScript 库，所以我建立了一个真正的一个，它叫 honkiby 和
have a fake JavaScript library so I built
a real one, it's called Honkify and
如果你还记得那个无标题的鹅游戏，它把所有的链接
if you remember the untitled goose game,
what it does is it makes all of the links
在你的网站按喇叭，而不是实际点击你想要的东西。
on your site honk instead of actually
clicking through the thing you wanted to.
所以这是一个拖延的好方法。
So that was a great way to procrastinate.
我们还要定制主题。
We're also gonna customize the theme.
所以我们要把文档主题安装到这个宏飞站点上，然后
So we're going to install the the docs
theme on to this hongfei site and then
我们将自定义的主题使用选项，使它看起来像洪飞网站。
we'll customize the theme using options so
that it looks like the hongfei site.
我们将使用组件阴影来扩展主题 ui
We'll use component shadowing
to extend Theme UIs so
我们可以覆盖颜色，字体之类的东西。
we'll be able to override colors,
fonts, things like that.
然后我们将从头开始建立一个网站。
Then we're going to build
a site from scratch.
我们将为内格罗尼建立一个粉丝网站，这是我目前最喜欢的鸡尾酒。
We'll build a fan site for Negroni
which are my current favorite cocktail.
我们会使用这个文档主题，但是我们不会把它用在文档上。
And we'll use that docs theme, but
we're not gonna use it for docs.
我们要用它来
We're gonna use it for
也就是说，我们得对它做些改动。
recipes, which means that we're gonna
have to make some modifications to it.
因此，我们将再次扩展主题 UI。
So we'll extend Theme UI again.
然后我们会做一些有趣的事情。
But then we're going to do some fun stuff.
我们要进入 Cloudinary 来管理图像
We're gonna get into
Cloudinary to manage images so
我们的图像传输线又快又好。
that our image pipeline is nice and fast.
我们只是要上传东西到 Cloudinary，让 Cloudinary 来做这些工作
We're just gonna upload things to
Cloudinary, let Cloudinary do the work so
我们的建筑管道不会慢下来。
that our buildings pipeline
doesn't slow down.
我们还会使用组件跟踪来定制组件,
We're also gonna use component
shadowing to customize components,
因为我们不需要任何参考文件。
because we don't necessarily
want any reference to docs.
我们想要更新它来参考食谱，所以
We want to update that
to reference recipes, so
我们也要做这些开关。
we'll be making those switches as well.
然后我们会安装第二个主题，看看它们是如何组合在一起的。
And then we'll just install a second
theme to see how that composes together.
所以我们要安装一个我之前构建的活动主题。
So we'll install an events
theme that I built before.
我们只需要把它插进去，看看它是怎么工作的。
And we'll just plug that in and
see how it works.
最后，我们将设置一个动态应用程序，使用客户端 GraphQL
And then finally, we're gonna set up a
dynamic app that uses client side GraphQL
使用 Apollo，我们将配置客户端路线和
with Apollo,
we will configure client only routes and
所以这将是一个可链接的搜索结果。
Gatsby, so
this will be a linkable search results.
所以我们要使用里克和莫蒂 API 查找字符。
So we're gonna use the Rick and
Morty API to look up characters.
每当你搜索
And whenever you search for
你想要的东西，可以发送一个链接到该搜索结果说
something you want to be able to send
a link to that search results said
然后让他们点击查看相同的搜索结果。
to someone and have them click on it and
see the same search results.
所以我们要建立，将建立重定向和废除这样
So we're gonna build that will
set up redirects and nullify so
当你部署它的时候，它能在本地工作
that this works locally and
when you deploy it, and
然后我们用反应钩建立一个搜索表格。
then we'll use react hooks
to set up a search form.
结果页面，正如我所提到的，将是可链接的。
And the results page,
as I mentioned, will be linkable.
所以，说了这么多，让我们开始吧。
So, with all of that being said,
let's get started.
欢迎您编写代码。
You are welcome to code along.
我有跑得有点快的倾向。
I have a tendency to go a little bit fast.
所以你也可以随心所欲地坐下来吸收它。
So also feel free to just sit back and
absorb it.
所有这些都会在网上公布
And all of this is gonna be online and
你可以重新检查两个不同的地方。
you'll be able to revisit it
check out two different points.
但是如果你想克隆回收商,
But yeah, if you want to if
you want to clone the repo,
在 jlang storf / gatsby-中级。
it's at jlang storf/gatsby-intermediate.
我们将从开始分支开始。
And we'll be starting
from the start branch.